From all outward appearances,
من جميع المظاهر الخارجية,
John had everything going for him.
بدى جون كأن كا شيء يمضي لصالحه
He had just signed the contract
قام للتو بالتوقيع على عقد
to sell his New York apartment
بيع شقته في نيو يورك
at a six-figure profit,
بربح يقدر بستة خانات,
and he'd only owned it for five years.
وكان قد امتلكها لخمسة سنين فقط.
The school where he graduated from with his master's
الجامعة التي تخرج منها بدرجة الماجستير
had just offered him a teaching appointment,
عرضت عليه منصب التدريس فيها
which meant not only a salary,
وهو مايعني ليس فقط الراتب,
but benefits for the first time in ages.
لكن ايضا منافع لاول مره في عمره.
And yet, despite everything going really well for John,
ولكن وبالرغ من ان كل شيئ كان يمضي بشكل جيد لاجل جون,
he was struggling,
الا انه كان يقاوم,
fighting addiction and a gripping depression.
يصارع الادمان واجتياح الاكتئاب.
On the night of June 11th, 2003,
في ليلة الحادي عشر من يوليو 2003,
he climbed up to the edge
تسلق الى حافة
of the fence on the Manhattan Bridge
حاجز جسر مانهاتن
and he leaped to the treacherous waters below.
وقفز الى المياه الغادرة بالأسفل.
Remarkably --
اللافت للنظر--
no, miraculously --
لا, بأعجوبة --
he lived.
ظل على قيد الحياة.
The fall shattered his right arm,
القفزة حطمت ذراعه الايمن,
broke every rib that he had,
حطمت كل ما لديه من اضلاع,
punctured his lung,
ثقبت رئته,
and he drifted in and out of consciousness
وكان يتارجح بين الوعي والا وعي
as he drifted down the East River,
بينما كان يجنح اسفل يست ريفر,
under the Brooklyn Bridge
تحت جسر بروكلين
and out into the pathway of the Staten Island Ferry,
خروجا الى ممر ستالين ايسلاند فيري
where passengers on the ferry
حيث راكب في مركب نهري
heard his cries of pain,
سمع بكاؤه من الالم
contacted the boat's captain
فأخبر ربان المركب
who contacted the Coast Guard
الذي قام بالاتصال بخفر السواحل
who fished him out of the East River
الذي التقطه من ايست ريفر
and took him to Bellevue Hospital.
ونقله الى مستشفى بيليفوي
And that's actually where our story begins.
وهناك بالفعل بدأت قصتنا.
Because once John committed himself
لانه حالما عاهد جون نفسه
to putting his life back together --
باستجماع حياته مرة اخرى --
first physically, then emotionally,
اولا جسديا ومن ثم عاطفيا,
and then spiritually --
وثم روحيا--
he found that there were very few resources available
وجد انه يوجد هناك قليل من الموارد
to someone who has attempted to end their life
متاحة لشخص حاول انهاء حياته
in the way that he did.
بالطريقة التي قام بها.
Research shows
الابحاث تظهر
that 19 out of 20 people
ان 19 من كل 20 شخص
who attempt suicide
من المقدمين على الانتحار
will fail.
سوف يفشلون.
But the people who fail
لكن الاشخاص الذين يفشلون
are 37 times more likely to succeed
ينجحون بمعدل 37 مرة
the second time.
في المحاولة الثانية.
This truly is
وهذا في الحقيقة
an at-risk population
قطاع من السكان في خطر
with very few resources to support them.
ومع القليل من الموارد لدعمهم
And what happens
وما يحصل
when people try to assemble themselves back into life,
عندما يحاول الاشخاص استجماع نفسهم للحياة مرة اخرى,
because of our taboos around suicide,
وبسبب المحرمات المنسوجة حول الانتحار,
we're not sure what to say,
لسنا متأكدين ماذا يتوجب علينا قوله
and so quite often we say nothing.
وفي كثير من الاحيان لا نقول شيئا
And that furthers the isolation
وذلك يعزز العزلة
that people like John found themselves in.
الذي يجد اشخاص مثل جون انفسهم فيها.
I know John's story very well
اعرف قصة جون جيدا
because I'm John.
لانني انا جون.
And this is, today,
واليوم
the first time in any sort of public setting
هي المرة الاولى في اي شكل من الظهور العلني
I've ever acknowledged
اعترف فيها
the journey that I have been on.
بالرحلة التي كنت فيها
But after having lost a beloved teacher in 2006
ولكن بعد خسارة مدرس محبوب في 2006
and a good friend last year to suicide,
وصديق عزيز في السنة الماضية منتحرا
and sitting last year at TEDActive,
وجلوسي في العام الماضي في تيد اكتيف
I knew that I needed to step out of my silence
علمت انه علي الخروج من صمتي
and past my taboos
وتخطي مخاوفي
to talk about an idea worth spreading --
والحديث عن فكرة تستحق الانتشار--
and that is that people
و ذلك ليتمكن الاشخاص
who have made the difficult choice
الذين اتخذو قرارا صعبا
to come back to life
بان يعودوا للحياة
need more resources and need our help.
يحتاجون المزيد من الموارد ويحتاجون مساعدتكم
As the Trevor Project says, it gets better.
وكما يقول مشروع تريفو. انه يتحسن
It gets way better.
يتحسن بشكل كبير
And I'm choosing to come out
واخترت الخروج
of a totally different kind of closet today
اليوم بخاتمة مختلفة تماما
to encourage you, to urge you,
لاشجعكم,لاحثكم,
that if you are someone
انه اذا كنت احد الذين
who has contemplated or attempted suicide,
فكرو او حاولوا الانتحار,
or you know somebody who has,
او تعرف شخص ما فعل ذلك
talk about it; get help.
ان تتحدث عن ذلك , واحصل على المساعدة
It's a conversation worth having
انه حوار يستحق القيام به
and an idea worth spreading.
وفكرة تستحق الانتشار.
Thank you.
شكرا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)